A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Correspondence with United States Senators and Representatives FA1411
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence with U.S. Representatives, 1969-1986; 2
  - Brademas, John - Indiana, 1969 September-1975 December (Box 4, Folder 118)
    HR 2966 Child and Family Services Act, educational research and development, HR 5988 National Institute of Education, National Foundation for the Arts and Humanities, Exploratorium in San Francisco, AERA talk - anthropologists, Energy Policy Project, Bakunin project, Educational Amendment of 1972, National Institute of Education
  - Bray, William Gilmer - Indiana, 1970 October (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - Breckinridge, John - Kentucky, 1973 November-1974 January (Box 4, Folder 120)
    Carthage excavation Northern Kentucky State College grant application
  - Brinkley, Jack - Georgia, 1975 January (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Brown, Clarence J. - Ohio, 1970 September-1982 September (Box 4, Folder 122)
    Warren Center of Learning in Springfield, Ohio; Wilberforce University
  - Broyhill, Joel T. - Virginia, 1972 January-August (Box 4, Folder 123)
    Drug abuse youth program, Voice of Government Employees, Inc.
  - Buchanan, John H., Jr. - Alabama, 1977 July-August (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Burke, James A. - Massachusetts, 1970 June-1978 March (Box 4, Folder 125)
    Correction to Congressional Record, Dorchester Comprehensive Community Development Project Proposal
  - Burke, Yvonne Brathwaite - California, 1973 January-1976 August (Box 4, Folder 126)
    "Direction '76: Political Power Through Unity" - Congressional Black Caucus, Environmental Teacher Center, Raymond Sontag Travelling Fellowship Berkeley
  - Burton, John L. - California, 1976 January (Box 4, Folder 127)
    Consumer Action
  - Burton, Phillip - California, 1976 January (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Bush, George - Texas, 1970 May-June (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Caputo, Bruce - New York, 1977 September (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Carey, Hugh L. - New York, 1972 November (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Carman, Gregory W. - New York, 1982 May-August (Box 4, Folder 132)
    Polish refugees
  - Carter, Tim Lee - Kentucky, 1971 February-1973 March (Box 4, Folder 133)
    University of California at Los Angeles grant for the continuation of Charles H. Sawyer's research, scholarship program for children of miners killed in the Leslie County mine explosion
  - Casey, Bob - Texas, 1974 February-1975 July (Box 4, Folder 134)
    Texas Southern University, education
  - Cavanaugh, John J. - Nebraska, 1977 June (Box 4, Folder 135)
    List of Ford Foundation grant-making activities in Nebraska
  - Chamberlain, Charles E. - Michigan, 1974 February-March (Box 4, Folder 136)
    Antarctic icebergs as a freshwater source
  - Chisholm, Shirley - New York, 1971 March-1982 February (Box 4, Folder 137)
    Institute for Mathematics and Science Training, Grand-Metro Garden Spot of the St. Nicholas Neighborhood Preservation and Housing Rehabilitation Corporation, New York Amsterdam News
  - Clark, Frank M. - Pennsylvania, 1972 May (Box 4, Folder 138)
    Research study grant request - European Physical Education classes compared to United States Physical Education classes
  - Clausen, Don H. - California, 1971 October (Box 4, Folder 139)
    Young Americans for Responsible Action (YARA)
  - Cleveland, James C. - New Hampshire, 1973 April-1974 March (Box 4, Folder 140)
    James C. Cleveland's Statement Before the Committee on Ways and Means on the Subject of Foundations and Charitable Institutions; Impact of Foundations on New London, New Hampshire
  - Cochran, Thad - Mississippi, 1973 April (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Cohen, William S. - Maine, 1974 March (Box 4, Folder 142)
    Request for scholarship
  - Collins, James M. - Texas, 1969 April-1981 September (Box 4, Folder 143)
    Impact of television on young people - need for business leader documentary, education for responsible citizenship
  - Conable, Barber - New York, 1973 July-1984 February (Box 4, Folder 144)
    Clippings related to Conable's career
  - Conlan, John B. - Arizona, 1975 January (Box 4, Folder 145)
    Arizona Job Colleges of Casa Grande, Arizona; Navajo Community College in Arizona
  - Cordova, Jorge L. - Puerto Rico, 1971 August-October (Box 4, Folder 146)
    Education and learning in Puerto Rico
  - Corman, James C. - California, 1973 April (Box 4, Folder 147)
    Grant to Professor Charles Sawyer
  - Corrada, Baltasar - Puerto Rico, 1984 February (Box 4, Folder 148)
    Little League Baseball Team - Morovis Sporting Club
  - Cotter, William R. - Connecticut, 1979 January (Box 4, Folder 149)
    University of Hartford, Hartford Community College, and Hartford State Technical College
  - Cowger, William O. - Kentucky, 1970 August-September (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Culver, John C. - Iowa, 1969 April-1974 April (Box 4, Folder 151)
    Foreign economic policy
  - Daniel, Robert W., Jr. - Virginia, 1977 June-July (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - Daniels, Dominick V. - New Jersey, 1970 February-1975 April (Box 4, Folder 153)
    Comprehensive Employment and Training Act (CETA), Tax Reform Act of 1969, testimony of Mitchell Sviridoff - Manpower
  - Danielson, George E. - California, 1972 March (Box 4, Folder 154)
    Education in American Government
  - Davis, John W. - Georgia, 1974 January (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Davis, Mendel J. - California, 1972 February-March (Box 4, Folder 156)
    McClennan-Banks Hospital
  - Dellenback, John - Oregon, 1969 September-1972 August (Box 4, Folder 157)
    Oregon Shakespeare Festival travel, education
  - Denholm, Frank E. - South Dakota, 1974 January 24 (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Dent, John H. - Pennsylvania, 1972 February-1978 November (Box 4, Folder 159)
    Voice of Government Employees - broadcast facility in Washington
  - Derwinski, Ed - Illinois, 1974 February-1975 May (Box 4, Folder 160)
    United Nations seminar and conference
  - Diggs, Charles C., Jr. - Michigan, 1971 September-1975 May (Box 4, Folder 161)
    Concept of East Theatre in Detroit, Changing Vistas in United States/African Economic Relations symposium, "The Role of the Subcommittee on Africa in the 94th Congress" symposium, US foreign policy toward South Africa, "World Food Security: A Global Priority," school boards of large urban school systems, Ford Foundation activities in South Africa, African-American National Conference on Africa, Congressman Diggs' press statement on his trip to South Africa
  - Dodd, Christopher J. - Connecticut, 1977 May (Box 4, Folder 162)
  - Dow, John G. - New York, 1971 April-1972 December (Box 4, Folder 163)
    Assistance to handicapped individuals, HR 6521 Federal reimbursement for state takeover of public school financing
  - Downing, Thomas N. - Virginia, 1972 November (Box 4, Folder 164)
    Hampton Institute
  - Drinan, Robert F. - Massachusetts, 1971 January-1980 July (Box 4, Folder 165)
    African-American Institute, New England Volunteer Employment Service Team, Hispanic Office of Planning and Evaluation (HOPE), housing
  - Duncan, John J. - Tennessee, 1983 September (Box 4, Folder 166)
    Knoxville College
  - Duncan, Robert B. - Oregon, 1977 February-1979 November (Box 4, Folder 167)
    Housing Authority of Portland, 1000 Friends of Oregon - land use program
  - Dunn, Jim - Michigan, 1981 July (Box 4, Folder 168)
  - Du Pont, Pierre S., IV - Delaware, 1971 April-May (Box 4, Folder 169)
    Federation of Southern Cooperatives
  - Dwyer, Florence P. - New Jersey, 1970 August (Box 4, Folder 170)
  - Edgar, Robert W. - Pennsylvania, 1980 December (Box 4, Folder 171)
    Northeast-Midwest Institute report - "Bringing the Federal Government Back Downtown: An Urban Policy Evaluation"
  - Esch, Marvin - Michigan, 1972 November-1975 June (Box 4, Folder 172)
    National Academy of Science's evaluation of the CETA program, tax reform
  - Eshleman, Edwin D. - Pennsylvania, 1971 December (Box 4, Folder 173)
    Street academy programs developed by the Urban League of Greater New York
  - Evans, Billy Lee - Georgia, 1977 March (Box 4, Folder 174)
  - Evins, Joe L. - Tennessee, 1970 September (Box 4, Folder 175)
    Chancellor Heard of Vanderbilt University - Address on campus unrest in the Congressional Record
  - Evans, Frank E. - Colorado, 1970 July (Box 4, Folder 176)
    Koshare Indian Museum project
  - Fenwick, Millicent - New Jersey, 1979 May-1982 December (Box 4, Folder 177)
    Education in Nigeria
  - Findley, Paul - Illinois, 1972 September-1973 January (Box 4, Folder 178)
    Congressional Record from October 2, 1972 - US foreign polcy, agriculture - "Famine Prevention"
  - Flood, Daniel J. - Pennsylvania, 1974 March-1977 June (Box 4, Folder 179)
    The Bicentennial Salute to The Captive Nations, Flood Relief by way of College Misericordia grant
  - Fraser, Donald M. - Minnesota, 1972 October-1978 October (Box 4, Folder 180)
    Human rights and US foreign policy, mass media, economic assistance to developing countries, Foreign Assistance Act, Program of International Studies of Fishery Arrangements, law of the sea issues
  - Frelinghuysen, Peter - New Jersey, 1973 August-1975 April (Box 4, Folder 181)
    1969 Tax Act, grants to Chatham and Hillsborough
  - Fulton, Richard H. - Tennessee, 1975 April (Box 4, Folder 182)
  - Galifianakis, Nick - North Carolina, 1970 May-1972 October (Box 5, Folder 183)
    St. Augustine's College - minorities in higher education
  - Gallagher, Cornelius E. - New Jersey, 1970 October-1971 November (Box 5, Folder 184)
    Select Committee on Privacy, Human Values, and Democratic Institutions, National Shakespeare Company - Appalachian counties in Georgia summer festival
  - Giaimo, Robert N. - Connecticut, 1976 November (Box 5, Folder 185)
    New England Energy Policy Council
  - Gilman, Benjamin A. - New York, 1983 October-1984 July (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - Glover, Michael G. - Kansas, 1974 January (Box 5, Folder 187)
    Scholarship funds for minority convicts
  - Gore, Albert, Jr. - Tennessee, 1977 November-1982 October (Box 5, Folder 188)
    Arms control proposals, Democratic Leadership Conference, Foundation activities in Tennessee
  - Grassley, Charles E. - Iowa, 1977 January (Box 5, Folder 189)
    Congressional Record regarding Henry Ford II's decision to leave the Board of the Ford Foundation
  - Grasso, Ella T. - Connecticut, 1972 November-1973 May (Box 5, Folder 190)
    The Greater Hartford Process, Inc. and Midstate Regional Planning Agency of Connecticut
  - Green, Edith - Oregon, 1971 January-1974 May (Box 5, Folder 191)
    Study of public school finance system in Oregon, higher education, Equal Rights Amendment, Pay As You Earn (PAYE) project
  - Griffiths, Martha - Michigan, 1973 June-August (Box 5, Folder 192)
    Urban Institute, Educational Staff Seminar, Subcommittee on Fiscal Policy of the Joint Economic Committee public welfare programs review
  - Gubser, Charles S. - California, 1971 August (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - Gude, Gilbert - Maryland, 1971 September-1973 June (Box 5, Folder 194)
    African Conference, Saint Maurice Day School - Work Apprenticeship Program
  - Haley, James A. - Florida, 1970 August-1974 January (Box 5, Folder 195)
    American Indians
  - Halpern, Seymour - New York, 1969 April (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - Hanna, Richard - California, 1973 October-1974 December (Box 5, Folder 197)
    International Cultural and Trade Center, International Science and Technology Transfer Institute, Global Communication Facility, SER/Jobs for Progress, Inc.
  - Hansen, Orval - Idaho, 1970 December-1971 May (Box 5, Folder 198)
    Federal aid to public education, National Legal Services Corporation
  - Harkin, Tom - Iowa, 1977 March (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - Hathaway, William D. - Maine, 1971 November-1973 April (Box 5, Folder 200)
    Grants for Maine municipalities, Native American Rights Fund grant
  - Heckler, Margaret M. - Massachusetts, 1976 August-1978 July (Box 5, Folder 201)
    Congresswomen's Caucus Corporation, New England Volunteer Employment Service Team
  - Heftel, Cecil "Cec" - Hawaii, 1977 June (Box 5, Folder 202)
    List of activities supported by the Ford Foundation in Hawaii
  - Heinz, John - Pennsylvania, 1984 July-1985 August (Box 5, Folder 203)
    10th Anniversary of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 conference (ERISA), Special Committee on Aging pension policy conference
  - Holifield, Chet - California, 1972 May (Box 5, Folder 204)
    Energy Policy Project
  - Holtzman, Elizabeth - New York, 1973 March-1979 October (Box 5, Folder 205)
    Congresswomen's Caucus, Rules of Evidence for the Federal Courts
  - Howe, Allan T. - Utah, 1976 January (Box 5, Folder 206)
    Navajo Tribal Council
  - Huber, Robert J. - Michigan, 1974 September (Box 5, Folder 207)
    Finances of the Performing Arts
  - Hungate, William L. - Missouri, 1970 September 22 (Box 5, Folder 208)
    Congressional Record - changing the Tax Reform Act
  - Johnson, Harold T. (Bizz) - California, 1977 March (Box 5, Folder 209)
  - Jones, James R. - Oklahoma, 1975 April-1980 May (Box 5, Folder 210)
    Southwest Educational Development Laboratory in Austin, bill to amend the IRS code of 1954
  - Jones, Robert E. - Alabama, 1971 September (Box 5, Folder 211)
    Archaeological development of Cathedral Caverns - Jay Gurley
  - Koch, Edward I. - New York, 1970 April-1977 September (Box 5, Folder 212)
    Response to Koch's statement in Congressional Record regarding Ford Foundation's contributions to New York City, environmental research in the Middle East, Human Rights in Indonesia and the Philippines, Pace University, clarification of issue regarding assistance to Police Department of New York City from the CIA "pushed by Ford Foundation", The 51st State, conference on conditions of correctional institutions, Congressional Record - The Federal Government Should Not Tax Museums and Libraries Open to the Public
  - Landrum, Phil M. - Georgia, 1971 November (Box 5, Folder 213)
    Appalachian counties in Georgia summer Festival - National Shakespeare Company
  - Langen, Odin - Minnesota, 1970 November (Box 5, Folder 214)
  - Leggett, Robert L. - California, 1971 January-1974 March (Box 5, Folder 215)
    Council on United States/Republic of China (Taiwan) Relations, Deganawidah-Quetzalcoatl University
  - Long, Clarence D. - Maryland, 1977 June-1982 August (Box 5, Folder 216)
    Polish refugees, financial aid to individual constituents
  - Long, Gillis - Louisiana, 1974 January (Box 5, Folder 217)
  - Lundine, Stanley N. - New York, 1979 October-November (Box 5, Folder 218)
  - McCarthy, Richard Dean (Max) - New York, 1970 July (Box 5, Folder 219)
  - McCloskey, Paul N., Jr. - California, 1979 March-1980 June (Box 5, Folder 220)
    African-American Institute, collaboration among organizations engaged in public sector contraceptive research and development
  - McClure, James A. - Idaho, 1970 November-1971 January (Box 5, Folder 221)
    World protein nutrition
  - McCormack, John W. - Massachusetts, 1972 February (Box 5, Folder 222)
  - McCormack, Mike - Washington, 1974 November-1977 September (Box 5, Folder 223)
    National energy research
  - McDonald, Larry P. - Georgia, 1976 March-1983 September (Box 5, Folder 224)
    Obituary, Anti-Ford Foundation entries in the Congressional Record - Ocean Hill-Brownsville, LaRaza, Inter-Religious Foundation for Community Organization (IFCO), Commission on US-Latin American Relations
  - McKay, K. Gunn - Utah, 1971 June-1975 January (Box 5, Folder 225)
    Navajo Community College, allegations against the Ford Foundation in American Opinion Magazine
  - McMillan, John L. - South Carolina, 1972 July-August (Box 5, Folder 226)
    Pamplico, South Carolina - grant to build a library
  - McSpadden, Clem - Oklahoma, 1973 March-April (Box 5, Folder 227)
    Assistance to Tenkiller Dependent School District
  - Maguire, Andrew - New Jersey, 1976 December-1979 May (Box 5, Folder 228)
    Fair Access to Higher Education Act, HR 14147 Tax Act of 1969, Guaranteed Student Loan (GSL) program, Old Church Cultural Center of Demarest, New Jersey
  - Mahon, George - Texas, 1974 February-1975 September (Box 5, Folder 229)
    Policy on Payment of Overhead to Grantees, East Lubbock Business Association of Lubbock, TX
  - Marsh, John O., Jr. - Virginia, 1970 October (Box 5, Folder 230)
  - Martin, James G. - North Carolina, 1974 January (Box 5, Folder 231)
  - Mathias, Robert B. (Bob) - California, 1970 September-1971 May (Box 5, Folder 232)
    Misinformation regarding Huey Newton and the Black Panthers, US cotton production techniques
  - Matsunaga, Spark M. - Hawaii, 1976 October 18 (Box 5, Folder 233)
    Hawaiian Coalition of Native Claims, increasing private foundation responsiveness to the needs of ethnic minorities, PBS plan for network distribution by satellite study
  - Melcher, John - Montana, 1970 March-1972 November (Box 5, Folder 234)
    Urban Affairs Institute, Crow Indians
  - Meeds, Lloyd - Washington, 1971 May-1976 June (Box 5, Folder 235)
    Bacone College, Native American Rights Fund, Alaska Native Foundation, Whatcom Museum of History and Art - Grant 700-241
  - Mikva, Abner J. - Illinois, 1976 February-1976 March (Box 5, Folder 236)
    Alcohol abuse
  - Mills, Wilbur D. - Arkansas, 1970 June-1976 March (Box 5, Folder 237)
    Retirement of Wilbur Mills, alcoholism, Referral and Tutorial Services, Election Laws Institute, Allen Young YMCA in North Little Rock, Our Brothers Place, Tax Reform Act of 1969, Founding Ceremony for the Wilbur D. Mills Center for the Study of the Social Sciences at Hendrix, Robert A. Arms Para-Professional School of Alcoholism, Philander Smith College, American Council for Rehabilitation Through Education and Economic Development (A CREED), Energy Policy Project, Kimball Foundation, Bethune-Cookman College, Travel Program for Foreign Diplomats, All, Incorporated, Council for Family Financial Education, solid waste incinerator, Arkansas Baptist Medical Center, International Congress on Alcoholism, Hendrix College